<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PathPearls</title>
    <link>https://pathpearls.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PathPearls</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 09:57:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pathpearls.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pregnancy in SCD</title>
      <link>https://pathpearls.com/posts/20210407-scdpregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 09:57:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pathpearls.com/posts/20210407-scdpregnancy/</guid>
      <description>Pregnancy Complications in Sickle Cell Disease *Summary: patients with sickle cell disease (SCD) have a higher risk of typical pregnancy complications than those without SCD in addition to complications related to the underlying pathophysiology of the disease.
Pathophysiology Cardiovascular, respiratory, hematologic, and endocrine adaptations that normally occur in pregnancy may be particularly challenging in women with SCD. For example, cardiovascular output and total blood volume (primarily plasma volume) normally increase in the first trimester but this can exacerbate cardiovascular stress on a background of chronic organ and vascular damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pathpearls.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 11:04:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pathpearls.com/about/</guid>
      <description>PathPearls  Source of practical pearls from the literature for anatomical &amp;amp; clinical pathologists in practice or in preparation for board exams  Author &amp;amp; Creator: Rachel Jug  Anatomical &amp;amp; Clinical Pathologist specialized in Cytopathology &amp;amp; Transfusion Medicine Trained at RCSI, Duke, and University of Toronto (current)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 &amp; Pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://pathpearls.com/posts/20210205-covid19pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 10:28:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pathpearls.com/posts/20210205-covid19pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 Updates RE: Pregnancy I have a lot pregnant friends and family members right now so Archives&#39; latest slew of articles on the effects of COVID-19 on pregnant women and their infants particularly piqued my interest. Here are a few poignant pearls I took away:
Coronaviruses in Pregnancy - Analysis of 38 women with COVID-19 and review of prior coronaviruses&#39; impacts on pregnancy SARS-CoV1
 25% fatality rate in pregnant women Complications to fetus: miscarriage, intrauterine growth restriction, preterm birth No vertical transmission  MERS</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
